[{
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT related to the World Trade Organization (WTO)?",
    "option1": "Multifiber Agreement",
    "option2": "General Agreement on Trade and Services",
    "option3": "Multilateral Agreement on Investment",
    "option4": "Agreement on Agriculture",
    "answer": "Multilateral Agreement on Investment"
},
{
    "question": "In which year Board for Reconstruction of Public Sector Enterprises was constituted?",
    "option1": "2000",
    "option2": "2002",
    "option3": "2004",
    "option4": "2006",
    "answer": "2004"
},
{
    "question": "In which of the following countries maximum number of Branches of Indian Banks are located? ",
    "option1": "UK",
    "option2": "USA",
    "option3": "Honkong",
    "option4": "Australia",
    "answer": "UK"
},
{
    "question": "From the given options, bring out the one which is not a function / power of Reserve Bank of India: ",
    "option1": "To assume the responsibility of meeting directly or indirectly all reasonable demands for accommodation",
    "option2": "To hold cash reserves of the commercial banks and make available financial accommodation to them",
    "option3": "To enjoy monopoly of the note issue",
    "option4": "To assume the responsibility of statistical analysis of data related to macro economy of India",
    "answer": "To assume the responsibility of statistical analysis of data related to macro economy of India"
},
{
    "question": "In which of the following countries  prevalent the Pay as you earn (PAYE) , a withholding tax system?",
    "option1": "USA",
    "option2": "UK",
    "option3": "Australia",
    "option4": "Germany",
    "answer": "UK"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following imaginary circumstances, the Reserve bank of India will opt to sell Government securities in the open market?",
    "option1": "When the Foreign funds inflow is meek",
    "option2": "When there is enormous Foreign Funds Inflow in the Indian Economy",
    "option3": "When banks have low liquidity and need liquidity",
    "option4": "When Government of India asks the RBI to sell securities",
    "answer": "When there is enormous Foreign Funds Inflow in the Indian Economy"
},
{
    "question": "Note Printing Press that belongs to RBI is located in?",
    "option1": "Nasik",
    "option2": "Dewas",
    "option3": "Mysore",
    "option4": "Chennai",
    "answer": "Mysore"
},
{
    "question": "Which among the following is the correct character of the Foreign Exchange Markets?",
    "option1": "Foreign Exchange markets are localized markets",
    "option2": "Foreign Exchange markets operate within a country’s time zone",
    "option3": "Foreign Exchange markets are used only for trade related transactions",
    "option4": "Foreign Exchange markets are dynamic and round the clock markets",
    "answer": "Foreign Exchange markets are dynamic and round the clock markets"
},
{
    "question": "Which among the following body regulates Mutual Funds in India?",
    "option1": "RBI",
    "option2": "SEBI",
    "option3": "NABARD",
    "option4": "AMFI",
    "answer": "SEBI"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is the least preferred option by government for deficit financing?",
    "option1": "Printing of currency notes",
    "option2": "Loans from World bank and IMF",
    "option3": "Disinvestment of government holdings",
    "option4": "Open sale of government securities and bonds in market",
    "answer": "Printing of currency notes"
},
{
    "question": "What is the full form of LIBOR (The interest rate at which banks offer to lend funds in the interbank market)",
    "option1": "Liverpool Inter Bank Offered Rate",
    "option2": "Los Angeles Inter Bank Offered Rate",
    "option3": "Las Vegas Inter Bank Offered Rate",
    "option4": "London Inter Bank Offered Rate",
    "answer": "London Inter Bank Offered Rate"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is used by RBI for sterilization of the Capital Inflows?",
    "option1": "Base Rate System",
    "option2": "CRAR Obligations",
    "option3": "Open Market Operations",
    "option4": "Credit Authorization Scheme",
    "answer": "Open Market Operations"
},
{
    "question": "The “Inclusive Growth and Development Report” is published by which of the following organisations?",
    "option1": "World Bank",
    "option2": "World Economic Forumi",
    "option3": "Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development",
    "option4": "International Monetary Fund",
    "answer": "World Economic Forum"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is not added in the calculation of national income of India?",
    "option1": "The value of goods and services",
    "option2": "The sold value of the old fridge",
    "option3": "Services rendered by the housewives",
    "option4": "Both b & c",
    "answer": "Both b & c"
},
{
    "question": "Which of the following is not a feature of a mixed economy?",
    "option1": "Open trade",
    "option2": "State ownership",
    "option3": "Private property",
    "option4": "Market forces",
    "answer": "Open trade"
}
]